Vikas Maskeri

Master of Management student at IIT Bombay specializing in Finance and Strategy vikasmaskeri@gmail.com

Summary

I am currently pursuing my 2nd year of Master of Management course from Shailesh J. Mehta School of Management, IIT Bombay which is one of the premier B-schools of India.

I am interested in developing a long-term career in finance. Therefore I have taken key responsibilities related to Finance in my present education such as being the Head of Finance Club and undertaking innovative activities that shall give me opportunities to build my finance skills and leadership qualities.

Prior to joining MBA program, I have graduated from Mumbai University with Bachelors in Engineering(B.E.) in the field of Information Technology. Post my BE, I have 2 years of experience as a Software Developer at Paladion Networks, a Deloitte Fastest 50 growing companies of Asia which provides complete solutions for internet security.

I have worked on several projects which were aimed at reducing the delivery times of software products, eliminate purchase of new hardware by migrating to cloud computing. I also took steps to deploy innovative solutions to increase the number of customers across geographies by using translation of the existing software to many international languages. I also created a customer-friendly platform that enabled one stop destination for all purchases for clients. For all the above efforts and more, I have received the highest performance ratings during my entire period of employment.

Specialties

Management, Marketing, Strategy, Finance, Information Technology, Information Security

Experience

Overall Coordinator, Finance Continuum 2011 at Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay July 2011 - Present (2 months)

Organized a day long event with Industry stalwarts from companies like Tata Capital, Aditya Birla Group, CARE ratings, Kotak securities, CitiBank, Nomura, KPMG, UAE Exchange and ANZ Capital discussing challenges and opportunities associated with "Financing this decade for growth and sustainability".

Audience of more than 300 comprising of management students, faculty members, research scholars and corporates.

Student at Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay

July 2010 - Present (1 year 2 months)

Member of "Moolyankan 2010", online Project Finance Simulation Game

Head, Finance Club at Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay

July 2010 - Present (1 year 2 months)

- 1. Responsible for the on-campus post-budget analysis session in association with NDTV & NDTV profit.
- 2. Conducted club sessions for students of IIT Bombay on topics of finance, economics and accounting.

Summer Intern at Procter & Gamble

May 2011 - June 2011 (2 months)

Title: Improvement of raw material utilization

- 1. Identified the areas of losses for the business unit.
- 2. Benchmarked the losses against international sites
- 3. Developed strategies to reduce the losses
- 4. Implemented 7 new systems for detecting, classifying and analysing the losses
- 5. Mentored 20 line members, engineers and managers about the systems developed by me and its usage.
- 6. Negotiated with vendors for procuring the appropriate systems and tools at competitive prices

Result: Reduced losses of Rs. 16 million on an annual basis with an improvement of 2.5 %

Trainee- Corporate Advisory at Prabhudas Lilladher

December 2010 - January 2011 (2 months)

- 1. Identifying opportunities of investments by Private equity funds in certain sectors of India such as infrastructure, lifestyle, power, healthcare etc.
- 2. Worked in the Corporate Advisory team to find possible exits from certain companies which were then a portfolio company of PE funds.
- 3. Generated leads for investment in certain companies and prepared pitchbooks for them by analyzing the valuations of such companies.

Software Developer- Products at Paladion Networks

October 2008 - May 2010 (1 year 8 months)

- 1. Developed a SaaS model for product purchasing and a integrated payment gateway solutions to make consumer experience more friendly and secure. This model eliminated application maintenance costs and substantially reduced product delivery times.
- 2. Implemented "Scrum", Agile project development methodology and reduced the product

development time.

- 3. Successfully developed a Proof of Concept (PoC) for testing the feasibility of Cloud computing and scaled up the size of operations from 3 clients to more than 20 clients. The new system reduced costs and increased reliability.
- 4. Developed an e-learning tool with support for many international languages which resulted in acquisition of clients in new geographies.
- 5. Implemented an SMS messaging system to inform clients and developers about emergency situations and hence decreased system downtimes and minimized impact on client's businesses.

Publications

Treat the disease, not the symptoms

Financial Express September 6, 2010

Authors: Vikas Maskeri

Recommendations to Government on tacking Naxalism in India

Skills

Ruby on Rails

Agile Project Management

(Expert, 2 years experience) (Expert, 2 years experience)

Scrum

Matlab

MySQL

JavaScript

Private Equity

Corporate Finance

Project Finance

Valuation

Equity Research

Technical Analysis

SAS

Education

Shailesh J. Mehta School of Management, IIT Bombay

MBA, Finance, Marketing, Strategy, 2010 - 2012

Activities and Societies: 1. Head of Finance Club

- 2. Coordinator of Finance Continuum
- 3. Coordinator of "Moolyankan 2011"

Fr. Conceicao Rodrigues Institute of Technologay

B.E., Information Technology, 2004 - 2008

Activities and Societies: 1. Event Head for the year 2006-07 for Vashi Chapter of Computer

Society of India (CSI)

2. Member of IEEE activities

Gokuldham High, School

SSC, 2000 - 2002

Activities and Societies: Conducted a 2 day workshop on "Indian astrology"

Canara High School, Mangalore

1994 - 2000

Honors and Awards

1. Winner of "Product Network Guide 2010 Award" for "Innovation".

R&D Member of Verity, a malware scanning tool using innovative methods to develop a unique product in the domain of internet security where other competitors include McAfee, AVG, Kaspersky etc.

- 2. National Finalist at "Finesse", mutual fund competition organized by L&T Mutual Fund at IIM Lucknow
- 3. Won 2nd Prize in "Convoluted", a Consulting case study competition at SJMSOM, IIT Bombay
- 4. Finalist at "Outcry", stock market simulation game held at TAPMI, Manipal
- 5. Among top 5 teams at "Green Shoe- IPO of an NBFC" event held at IMT Ghaziabad.
- 6. Finalist at Supply Chain Case study competition organized by GeP at SJMSOM, IIT Bombay
- 7. Finalist at IFMR, Chennai in equity research competition
- 8. Finalist at B-plan competition held at MFC, Delhi University

Interests

Management, Technology, Finance, Marketing

Vikas Maskeri

Master of Management student at IIT Bombay specializing in Finance and Strategy

vikasmaskeri@gmail.com



Contact Vikas on LinkedIn